Priority queue, a priority queue is a special type of queue in which each element is associated with
a priority value and elements are served on the basis of their priority.
That is, higher priority elements are served fairs first.
However, if elements with the same priority occur, they are served according to their order in the
queue.
In a queue, the first in, first out FIFA rule is implemented, whereas in priority queue, the values
are removed on the basis of priority.
The element with the highest priority is removed.
First, consider this priority queue elements with the highest priority is served first.
So if we deck we remove elements from this queue, we would remove that element with the highest priority
first.
OK.
And in you from but no.
Priority Queue Priority Queue can be implemented using an array, a link, at least a heap data structure
or a binary search tree.
Among these data structures, heap data structure provides an efficient implementation of priority queues.
Hence, he or we will be using the hip data structure to implement the priority queue in this theater,
so we will work with Priority Queue when we finished the three section and the hip section.
OK, so we will postpone creation of priority queue until we we understand and deal with that data structure.
Three.
And the heap data and the binary search tree.
So this is the priority queue and we are going to create this and implement it in C and Java later on
when we learn about the three.